Ethan Chennault

2361 Pacific View Ct, San Leandro • (510) 457-5290 • ethan.chennault.net • ethanolchennault@gmail.com

Summary Statement

Motivated and ambitious student, currently studying business and computer science at University of California, Irvine. Interested in positions that increase exposure to industry tools while bolstering experience in several fields of software engineering, including web applications, information retrieval, and project management.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages

Javascript, Typescript, Python, C++, Java

Database Technologies

SQL, Postgres, Firebase, Supabase, AWS, MongoDB

Web Technologies

HTML, CSS, React, Tailwind, Express, Next.js, Remix

Workflow Tools (and other)

Git, GitHub, Linux, Docker, Figma, Drizzle, Prisma

Experience

Student Assistant

June 2024 - Present

Lawrence Berkeley National Labs

Berkeley, CA

- Implemented and documented a full design system coonsisting of several dozen user interface components from Figma design specifications using React, Typescript, Storybook, and SCSS.
- Wrote tests utilizing snapshot testing with Jest and Playwright to provide consistency and 100% code coverage.

Research Assistant

Nov 2024 - Present

University of California, Irvine

Irvine, CA

- Implemented multithreading for BLANT, allowing an up to 16 times increase in run time via parallelism.
- Optimized the Makefile for BLANT, a graph analysis research tool, reducing build time by 20 percent.
- Utilized React and Express in the development of web applications and interfaces for research projects.

Summer Technology Intern

June 2022 - Aug 2022

Alameda County Information and Technologies Department

Oakland, CA

- Configured and repaired private networks systems with components switches, firewalls, and routers, allowing for faster communications and network connection in three new buildings.
- Uninstalled and disk wiped nonessential servers in the Oakland data center, optimizing the network.

Engineering Intern

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Hewlett Packard Enterprise

Remote

- Developed a Python script, to allow developer querying speed of real HPE customer servers.
- Created suites of unit and integration tests to ensure code quality across Windows and Linux operating systems.

Education

University of California, Irvine

September 2023 - Present

B.S. in Computer Science, B.S. in Business Information Management

GPA: 3.83, Dean's Honor List

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures & Algorithms, Information Retrieval, Intermediate Programming

San Leandro High School

August 2019 - June 2023

Projects

- **Search Engine:** Web search engine capable of handling over fifty thousands of documents, utilizing ranked retrieval based on tf-idf, and having a query response time of 100 milliseconds.
- **Sense:** Fullstack web application for managing a personal budget, inspired by YNAB, utilizing Postgres to handle hundreds of users and budgets, stored on a Postgres database with a React/TS frontend.
- **Redrawer:** Python script for re-creating images on Microsoft Paint by analyzing pixel color information and utilizing the Win32 API to efficiently redraw images with widths of up to 4 thousand pixels.

Additional

Languages: English (Native), Mandarin (Conversational)

GitHub: https://github.com/3thanOls

Extracurriculars: VP of Membership Development at Sigep, Cal Beta Alpha, volunteering at San Leandro Food Pantry